hi I'm Jim an engineer on the Reality Kit team
today my colleague Christopher
from the AR Kit team will
join me in guiding you through
how to get
started with building apps for special computing
let's dive in
we are excited
about a new platform for spatial computing
this platform
is built on familiar foundations for people to use
and for you to develop apps on
it opens up new and exciting possibilities
to blend real and virtual content
as well as using natural input
to interact with your app
and the whole system has been designed to protect
people's privacy
giving you the peace of mind
to focus on your apps experience
let's talk a bit about the fundamentals
to build up our vocabulary
and concepts of spatial computing
after that we'll go over the different ways to get
started with your app
then my colleague Christopher
will walk us through how to build your app
diving deeper into the details of special computing
now let's take a look at some of the fundamentals
first
let's cover what both familiar and new UI concepts
mean in spatial computing
by default apps launch into the shared space
this is where apps exist side by side
much like multiple apps on a Macdus space
people remain connected to their surroundings through
pass through
each app can have one or more windows
these are swift UI scenes that can be resized
and reflowed
like you would expect of a normal Mac OS window
they can contain traditional views and controls
as well as 3D content
allowing you to mix a match 2D and 3D
people can reposition a window
to the liking in the current space
just as one might expect
volumes allow an app to display 3D content
in a defined bounce
sharing the space with other apps
volumes are great for showcasing 3D content
for example Chessport
people can reposition volumes in space
and they can be viewed from different angles
volumes are swift UI scenes
allowing you to do layout in familiar ways
and they use the power of real ticket
to display your 3D content
sometimes you might want to have more control
of the level of motion in your app
maybe to focus while watching a video or to play a game
you can do this by opening a dedicated full space
where your apps Windows
Volumes and 3d objects are the
only one appearing across the view
in a full space
you can also take advantage of AR kits APIs
for example in addition to system provided gestures
you can get more detailed skeletal hand tracking
to really incorporate the structure of people's
hands into your experience
your app can use a full space in different ways
you can use pass through
to ground content in the real world
and keep people connected with their surroundings
and when you play spatial audio
and render 3D through Reality Kit
you will automatically take advantage
of the fact that the device will continually update
understanding
of the room to blend visuals and sound
into people surroundings
making them feel that these virtual audios
really belong in their room
you can also choose to render to fully immersive space
to fill up the entire field of view
this allows your app flexibility
to deliver on creative intent of your app
by customizing the lining of virtual objects
as well as the ability to choose audio characteristics
these are the foundational
elements of spatial computing
Windows Volumes and spaces
they give you a flexible tool set to build
apps that can span the continuum
of immersion
Christopher will talk more about this later
now that we introduce
the foundational elements of spatial computing
let's explore the ways we can interact with Windows
volumes and spaces
on this platform
we can interact with apps by simply
using our eyes and our hands
people can for example interact with a button
by looking at it
and tapping the fingers together to select
people can also reach out
and physically touch the same button in 3D space
for both these kinds of interactions
there is a variety of gestures that are possible
like taps long presses drags rotations
zooms and a lot more
the system detects these automatically and generates
touch events for your app to respond to
gestures are integrated well with Swift UI
the same gesture API works seamlessly with Reality Kit
entities
this allows people to easily interact
directly with your 3D scene elements
for example this could be useful to place a flag
directly onto this 3d model
or imagine controlling a virtual zipper
or
perhaps you want to interact and pick up virtual chess
pieces now if you want to do a game of bowling
or transform people's hands into a virtual club
you can do this through air kit skeletal hand tracking
here we can see an example how you can stack
cubes on the table using taps
and then smashing them onto the table with your hands
this is a powerful way
that you can bring app specific hands input
into the experience
and finally the system automatically brings input
from wireless keyboards
trackpads
and accessibility hardware right into your app
and the Game Controller Framework
lets you add support for wireless game
controllers as well
collaborating
exploring things
together is a fundamental part of special computing
we do this through Shareplay and the Group Activities
Framework
on this platform Asa macos
people can share any window
like this quick look experience
when people share a quick look 3d model
we sync the orientation
scale and animations between participants
making it easy to
collaborate while being in different locations
when people are collaborating
on something that is shown in their space
and that they physically point that
it is important that everyone in the shareplay session
had the same experience
this enables natural references
such as gestering to an object
and reinforces the feeling of being
physically together
we've added the concept of shared context to the system
the system manages this shared context for you
helping
make sure that participants in a Shareplay session
can all experience content in the same way
you can use
spatial persona templates to further customize
how people experience your content
to learn more
watch our sessions about
designing and building spatial shareplay experiences
for this platform
give me that the device has a lot of intimate knowledge
of the surroundings and people
we put a lot of architecture in place to protect
people's privacy
let's dive into that
privacy is a core
principle for guiding the design of this platform
we'll make it easy for you as a developer
to leverage APIs to take advantage of the
many capabilities
of the device
instead of allowing apps acts data from the sensors
directly
the system does that for you and provides apps with
events and visual cues
for example the system knows the eye position
and gestures of someone is hands in 3d space
and delivers that as touch events
also the system will render a hover effect
on a view when it's a focus of tension
but does not communicate
to the app where the person is looking
for many situations
the system provided
behaviors are sufficient for your app to respond
to interactions
in cases where you actually
do need access to more sensitive information
the system will ask the people
for their permission first
an example
would be asking user permission to access scene
understanding
to detect walls and furniture
or access to skeletal hand tracking
to bring custom interactions into your app
now that we've seen some of the capabilities
available for apps
let's move on to exploring
how we are developing those apps
everything starts with X Code
Apple's integrated development environment
X Code offers a complete
set of tools for developing apps
including project management support
visual editors for your UI
debugging tools assimilator and much more
and most importantly
X Code also comes with a platformesticate
which provides the complete set of frameworks and APIs
you'll use for developing your app
if your source file contains a Swift UI
preview provider
the preview canvas will automatically open up in X code
the preview canvas has been extended to support 3D
allowing you to visualize
real ticket code for your scene
including animations and custom code
this enables shorter iteration times
finding the right look and feel for your app
as you edit live code
and see the results of changes and tweaks directly
let's experiment a little bit here with
how the satellite
looks orbiting the earth
changing the orbital speed
and the size of the satellite
notice the preview reflects the code changes
making it easy to see the results
a quick experimentation in the code
X Code Previews
also has an object mode
that allows for quick previews of 3D layouts
for example seeing if your layout fits inside the
bounds of the view
this is great for building
tightly integrated scenes with both traditional UI
and new 3D visuals
X Code Preview
gives you a fantastic way to get the layout right
before you run your app
the simulator is a great way of
testing interactivity with your app
you can move
and look around in the scene using a keyboard
mouse or compatible game controller
and it's easy to interact with your app
by using simulated system gestures
the simulator comes with three
different simulated scenes
each with the day and night lighting
this makes it easy to see your app under
different conditions
the simulator is a great way to run and debung most
apps and to quickly iterate during development
with a very predictable environment
we've also extended
excode to support a number of runtime visualizations
while you are debugging
to help you quickly understand
and track down bugs by simply looking at the scene
here we have plane estimation visible
including semantic meaning of those planes
and the collision shapes in the scene
it's easy to toggle
visualizations you would like to focus on from
the debugger and
X code these visualizations were great
both in its simulator and in the device
when it becomes time
to polish your application's performance
and responsiness
we've got familiar tools like Instruments
Instruments is a powerful performance
analysis tool included with
X Code you can use instruments to provide you with
actionable insights of your running app
and for spatial computing
instruments 15 includes a new template
real Ticket Trace
providing even more and deeper insights
into new behaviors on the platform
the royalty get
trace template
has new instruments allowing developers to understand
GPU CPU
and system power impact of their app
and identify performance hotspots
you can easily observe and understand frame bottlenecks
and trace them back to vital metrics like
total triangle submitted
or number of reality kit entity simulated
this lets you quickly find
and address potential performance issues
for more details
check out the session Meat Reality Trace
we've also introduced a new
developer tool called Reality Composer Pro
it allows you to preview and prepare
3D content for your apps
Reactive Composer Pro
helps you get an overview of
all your assets and how they fit
together in your scene
a new feature that we're added to realticate
is particles
and you can use a workflow in Reality Composer Pro
to author and preview them
adding particles into your scene provides movement
life and endless possibilities
clouds rain and sparks
are just a few effects that you can build in a
short amount of time
adding audio
into your scenes and associate them with objects
is a breeze you can also spatially preview audio
which takes into account the shape
and context of your entire scene
most virtual objects will use reality kits
physically based material
to represent the variety of real world materials
reality kits use a sensor data to feed real world
lining information
into these materials
grounding them in people surroundings
real ticket
also has a couple of additional standard materials
available for your app
to use in common scenarios
for those times when you have a very specific need
perhaps to convey a creative intent
you can auto custom materials in reality Composer Pro
with an open standard Material X
you can do this through an easy to use note graph
without touching any code
and quickly preview them directly in the viewport
you can learn more about this in the session
Explore Materials
in Reality Composer Pro
when you're feeling good about your 3D content
you can send your scenes to your device
and test your content directly
this is great for iteration times
since you don't even have to build an app
to learn more
watch the session Meet Reality Composer Pro
another option that is available is Unity
Unity is bringing the ability for you to write apps for
spatial computing
with familiar workflows
and without any plugins required
you can bring your existing content over to power
new immersive experiences
to learn more
watch these sessions covering how to write
immersive apps with unity
now that we
understand some of the fundamental concepts and
tools available to us
let's see how we can start building apps
there are two ways to get started
either you design a brand new
app from the ground up to be spatial
or perhaps you have an existing app
that you want to bring into this new spatial platform
let's explore how we build a new app
designing an application from the ground up
to be spatial helps you to quickly embrace the new
unique capabilities
of spatial computing
to get started you can use
new app template for this platform
the app template has two new important options
first
you can choose your initial scene type to be either a
window or a volume
this generates the initial starting code for you
and it's easy to add additional scenes later
the second option
lets you add an entry point for an immersive
space to your app
by default your app will launch into this shared space
if you select immersive scene type to space
a second scene will be added to app
along with an example button
showing how to launch into this full space
and when you finish the assistant
you're presented with initial working app in Swift UI
that shows familiar buttons mixed in with 3D object
rendered with Reality Kit
to learn more watch the session
develop your first immersive app
we're also publishing code samples
each one of them illustrating
different topics to quickly get you up to speed
Destination Video shows you how to build a shared
immersive playback experience
that incorporates 3D video and spatial audio
Happy Beam is an example how you can create a game
that leverages an immersive space
including custom hand gestures
to create a fun game with friends
and Hello World
shows how to transition
between different visual modes with the 3D globe
Christopher will talk more in detail
about Hello World later
building and designing your app from the ground up
on this platform
offers opportunities to easily embrace
special computing concepts
however some of you might have
existing apps that you want to bring to
special computing
from the start iPad and iPhone apps look and feel great
if your app supports iPad
that variant will be preferred over iPhone
though iPhone only apps are fully supported
let's take a look at the recipes
apps shown here in the simulator
while this platform has its own darker style
iPad and iPhone apps retain a light mode style
windows can scale to allow ease of use
and rotations for apps are handled allowing you to see
different layouts
to find out more watch the session
run your iPad and iPhone apps in the shared space
to learn more about the systems built in behaviors
functional differences and how to test with a simulator
however running an existing iPad or iPhone app is
just the beginning
it's easy to add a destination in your
X code project for this platform with just a click
and after that we can simply select that target device
recompile and run
once you recompile
you get native spacing sicing and relay out
your windows and materials will all automatically move
to the platform's look and feel
ensuring legibility in any light condition
and your app
can take advantage of building capabilities
like highlighting for your custom controls
now here is Christopher
to show us how we can involve our apps further
using the concepts we covered so far
thanks Jim I'm gonna walk you through
how to build an application
that incorporates the elements you've Learned
previously let's start with Hello World
to explore some of the great
functionalities you can integrate
into your app
here's our sample in action
upon running the app in the simulator
Hello World launches with a window
into the shared space right in front of us
this is a familiar looking window made in Swift UI
and it contains different elements such as text
images and buttons
using tap gestures allows the navigation within the app
observe how our new view has embedded 3D content
Swift UI and 3D content now work together seamlessly
going back to our main window
and selecting planted earth
brings us to a new view
a new element appears
this is a volume
it contains a 3D model of the earth
alongside a few UI elements
by moving the window bar
the volume's position can be adjusted
anywhere in the surroundings
going back to our main window
again and selecting view Outer Space
brings up an invitation
for us to enter the solar system
from here we can enter space
which is shown here with an immersion style of full
our example renders planet earth and dims pass through
allowing us to focus on the content
with no distractions of the surroundings
now that we have seen how this looks in action
let's break down
some of the functionalities of Hello World
and show you how to use these concepts
in your own apps
as you've Learned from gym
there are multiple elements windows volumes and spaces
you can look at this as a spectrum
that your app can use to flex up and down
depending on what is best for people using your app
in a specific moment
you can choose to present one
or several windows in a shared space
allowing people to be more present
that can see pass through
and have a choice to have other app side by side
or you can choose to increase the immersion level
by having your app take over the space entirely
finding the most suitable elements for your apps
experience in a given moment
and flexing between them is an important consideration
when you design your app for spatial computing
next let's look further
into how to use Windows as part of your experience
windows serve as a starting point for your app
they are built with Swift UI using scenes
and they contain traditional views and controls
windows on this platform support mixing 2D
and 3D content
this means that your 3D content can be presented
alongside 2D
UI in a window
windows can be resized and repositioned in space
people can arrange them as per their liking
let's go back to our example
in Hello World
the content view holds our swift UI images
text and buttons
along with a call
to action to get more immersive content
creating a window is as
easy as adding a window group to our scene
inside the window group
we will display our content view
our content view can add 3D content
bringing a new dimension of death through your app
to do that you can use the new model 3D view
model 3D is similar to an image
making it easy to load
and display beautiful 3D content in your app
that is rendered by Reality Kit
to add Model 3D to your view
we initialize Model 3D
by passing the name of the satellite model
with this model 3D will find
and load the model and place it
into your view hierarchy
now
this window has the satellite embedded into the view
and can be seen coming out of the Z axis
adding a new dimension of depth your app
now that we have added a satellite
we can add interactions
interactions are fundamentally built into the system
and provided by Swift UI
Swift UI provides the gesture recognizers you are
already familiar with on apple platforms
such as tap on hover and rotate gesture
the platform provides new gesture recognizers
that are made for 3d interactions
like rotations in 3d space
taps on 3d objects and more
let's look at the code
that enables interactions with the satellite
we are going to enable a spatial tap gesture
so we can grab and move the satellite around
starting from model 3D we can now add a gesture inside
we add a drag gesture targeted to the satellite entity
we can then use the values passed in from the update
closure to move the satellite
let's see what that looks like
back in our satellite view
where our satellite is rendered
note the drag gesture allows me to tap
and drag the model moving with my interactions
as we've just seen
it's easy to mix 2D and 3D content
together with model 3D
these are just a few things you can do with a window
now let's look at another type of element volume
let's see what a volume has to offer
volume is an extension of a window
giving you similar functionality
a volume is a new style of window
that is ideal for 3D content
they can host multiple Swift UI
views containing your 2D
or 3D content
although volumes can be used in a full space
they're really built for the shared space
therefore
content must remain within the bounds of the volume
let's look at how to add a volume to your scene
you will start by creating a new window group
and setting its window style to volumetric
then you need to give it a default size
with the properties width
height and depth
the units of a volume can be specified in points
or meters let's look at this running in the simulator
when the application is presented
the volume is placed in front of the person
this volume has the dimensions we specified
along with the platform controls
the application title bar
which displays our app name making it easy to identify
which app this volume belongs to
the window bar enabling the volume to be positioned
and the close button
suspending the app when tapped closing the volume
currently our volume renders the 3d model of the earth
but you might want to start adding more
content in different behaviors
in order to do this
you can adopt Reality View as part of your app
reality view is a new view
that can be added to your scene
allowing for any number of entities to be managed
directly within Swift UI
Swift UI and Reality View
let you easily integrate your app
by connecting to Swift UI's manage state
and entity properties
this makes it easy to drive the behavior of
3d models with a source of truth from your apps data
model
conversion between coordinate spaces
it's easy
with conversion functions provided by Reality View
and reality view offers a way to position
swift UI elements
inside your 3DC
in through attachments
let's take a moment
to look at how we can use attachments
inside reality view
the Reality View initializer that we're going to use
takes three parameters
a mate closure
an update closure
and an attachments view builder
the make closure
allows you to create
entities and attach them to the route entity
the update closure
which is called whenever the state of the view changes
and lastly the attachments closure
is where we add our swift UI views with a tag property
that allows Reality View to translate our views
into entities
now let's work through an example
of how to use attachments with Reality View
adding an attachment is as easy as putting your
swift UI
view inside the attachment closure of Reality View
let's use this icon of a delicious pastry
to represent a location on our 3d globe
for each attachment
you must add a tag that gives the attachment a name
I'll name this one pin
to display the attachment
I'll add it to the content of my reality view
I'll do that in the update closure
by adding it to the root entity of the scene
here we can see the attachment made previously
rendering on the globe
above my favorite bakery location
as we've just seen
using Reality Kit unleashes powerful features
such as model 3D
reality view attachments and so many more
these can be easily integrated into your app
this is only scratching the surface
of what Reality Kit can do
if you want to know more
I encourage you to go and watch
build spatial experiences with Reality Kit
and
enhance your spatial computing app with Reality Kit
let's recap what we went through so far
a volume is a container that is
ideal for 2D and 3D content
volumes are built for the shared space
can coexist with windows
and are bounded to specific dimensions
next let's dive into our last type of element spaces
once your app is opening a dedicated full space
the system hides all other apps
leaving only your app visible
now you can place your apps window
volumes and content anywhere around you
thanks to Arkit and Reality Kit
your virtual content can
even interact with your surroundings
you could throw a virtual ball
into the room
and watch as it bounces off the wall
and then rolls on the floor
and with the addition of hand tracking
you can build custom gestures and interactions
or place the content relative to people's hands
many of these capabilities are coming from AR Kit
to go into more depth and
learn how you can leverage them in your app
be sure to check out
Meet AR Kit for a spatial computing session
with spaces your app can also offer
different levels of immersion
depending on which style is chosen
at creation time
Jim talked a bit
about the spectrum of immersion available in a full
space let's dive in
and learn more about how you can add more immersion
into your app
immersion style
is a parameter that can be passed in your full space
there are two basic styles called dot mixed
and dot full
mix
style layers your apps content on top of pass through
full style hides pass through and displays your content
only
you can also combine the two by choosing progressive
this style allows some pass through initially
but the person can change
the level of immersion all the way up to full
by turning the digital crown
located at the top of the device
let's go back to our example to explore immersion style
I'll start with the mix style and see how that looks
and because full space is a swift you I seen
I can use reality View to display the earth
here's the earth viewed from high orbit
and here's how I displayed the scene in my app
notice I didn't actually specify the immersion style
that's because when you create an immersive space
Swift UI assumes mixed styled by default
let's also take your app completely immersive
by adding a different immersion style
this time I'll use Immersion Style full
adding an immersive style
to the end of our immersive space is easy
we store the immersive style in our state variable
and then set the type to full
because we want to give
people the choice of
when they enter an immersive experience
it's a good idea to add a button
to allow the person
to decide if they want to enter this immersive style
now let's see the new immersive style in action
back in our app
I've taken Hello World from a single window
to fully immersed
allowing us to view planet earth from any angle
and that's just the beginning of what you can
do with your spatial app
let's see where you can go from here
in this session
we've covered the fundamentals
how to get started
and then
took you through the basics of building an app
we have some great sessions
that should be your next stop
about the principles of spatial design
or to learn about building apps with Swift UI
and with Reality Kit
or to begin creating your 3D content
with spatial computing
your app creation can venture into new exciting avenues
guided by your ingenuity
thanks for watching